Raymond Ly

Full Stack Web and Mobile Developer

Email: workrayz@gmail.com

Address: Ivano-Frankivsk, Ivano-Frankivsk Oblast, Ukraine, 76000

Github: workray

SUMMARY

I bring over 10 years of industry experience to the table and has worked with major tech companies like Yelp, Thumbtack, Airtable, and Namecheap.

I am an expert in bridging the gap between design and engineering and helping teams establish a design language that results in quality end-user experiences.

I am competent across the full stack web/mobile stack.

I value communication and trust most when working with remote teams.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Full-stack Developer

Namecheap May 2019 - Mar 2023

- Built a sales lead collection app for a large portfolio of high-value domains worth several million dollars.
- ullet Coded a new marketplace using React, AdonisJs, and GraphQL. Also contributed UI/UX design.
- Worked effectively with a remote team spread across three distant corners of the globe. https://www.vietnamcoracle.com

Senior Front-end Developer

All Social LLC Feb 2019 - Mar 2020

- Framework: React/React Native
- Flux architecture: Redux
- Data Caching / Offl ine: Redux Persist
 UI Toolkits: React Native Elements
- Icons: React Native Vector Icons
- · Code Style: ESLint
- Directory/fi le structure: Boilerplate

https://apps.apple.com/us/app/allsocial-app/id1662787514 https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com2go.social.all

Senior Mobile Developer

Katrine Birk Dec 2017 - Feb 2018

- Support multi languages(English and Danish)
- Custom video player(for vimeo)
- In-App-Purchase
- Push Notifi cation
- Fabric and Crashlytics
- Facebook
- Firebase

...

iOS: Swift

 $https://apps.apple.com/dk/app/tryk-og-glad-baby-zoneterapi/id1330810904?l=da\\ Android: Kotlin$



Senior Front-end Developer

Thumbtack Mar 2017 - Apr 2019

- Built a help center from the ground up using Create React App.
- Built a Salesforce integration layer using Salesforce's Force.com platform.
- Developed a dispute settlement application also with React and Redux.
- Worked eff ectively with a remote team in a distant time zone.

https://help.thumbtack.com

Front-end Software Engineer

Yelp Jun 2015 - Feb 2017

- Worked closely with the product team to build new features for the desktop and mobile site.
- Had a lead role on the small team that produced Yelp's fi rst UI style guide, and then made it available to the public. The style guide precipitated an organization-wide push towards modular design.
- Rebuilt completely Yelp's most important page (the business page) from scratch, using advanced CSS features for layout and interaction.
- Led the development of a complete overhaul of all email templates, including Yelp Weekly, which is sent to millions of users per week.
- Gained unique experience working on a large-scale software project with hundreds of contributors. Learned extensively about release engineering, including testing and deployment, as well as common web security vulnerabilities.

https://yelp.com/styleguide

Mobile Developer

Blingby Jan 2015 - Dec 2016

 Music and Video Player iOS: Objective-C Android: Java

Mobile Developer

Shelter Island Mapping Company, LLC Dec 2014 - Feb 2015

• МарВох

iOS: Swift

https://apps.apple.com/us/app/tides-near-me/id585223877

Android: Java

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=me.tidesnear.free

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

Sorbonne University

Ukraine | Apr 2011 - Mar 2015

PERSONAL SKILLS

Leadership 90%

Communication 100%

Self-motivation 100%

Decision Making 90%

Adaptability 90%

Native and Hybrid Mobile Development 100%

Full-Stack Web Development 100%

LANGUAGES

English

MOST PROUD OF

Physical Organization

Creative Thinking, Effectiveness, Productivity

Planning

Analyzing Issues, Decision Making, Project Management, Strategic Planning

Team Work

Collaboration, Delegation, Goal Setting, Group Leadership

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Mobile App Development Full Stack Development Front-end Development Back-end Development

HOBBIES

Basket Ball Reading